

Alexandru "Aly" MitanProgrammer, educator, artisan

email: alex.mitan@yahoo.com mobile: +40 751 372 232

Intro

In a nutshell, I create digital experiences, design learning paths for young people, and pursue several artforms. Outside of my longer-term positions, I have been on many small-scale projects, technical and artistic.

Everything I've ever done, I did with conviction, empathy and an understanding of systemics. I do not disappoint.

I am passionate about the natural sciences, programming and data science, game design, community building, and I have several ongoing passion projects. I am returning to programming as a career, and my experiences are diverse and built transferrable skills.

Key Skills

Programming: Analytics and art Probability and statistics Critical Thinking Public Speaking Community Leadership Course Design Mixed Arts

Work Experience

Hiatus and return

01/2021, 07/2024

This fills the gap for what I've been doing besides volunteering. I never stopped creating, coding, diversifying. I've programmed add-ons and mods for games, participated in code jams, studied statistics, probabilistic models and game design. I have worked on several paid and unpaid "gigs" on the technical and artistic side, each not big enough for its own entry (but I like sharing them). On the hands-on side, I built a lab, complete with a forge and toolkit for various crafts.

Session design - Erasmus+, ESN teambuilding

03/2023, 10/2022

Several smaller collaborations in teambuldings and exchanges, ran sessions on consent/boundaries, identity, social inclusion,

and supported the organising team.

Volunteer, Code of Conduct advocate - ESN

01/2021 - 07/2024, Erasmus Student Network

In ESN, I've used my experience as a trainer and community leader to empower fellow volunteers and hold activities (detailed above). I have also helped raise awareness of the Code of Conduct, and helped in conflict management within the community.

Trainer - "Skill UP"

08/2021, Erasmus+ Synergy in Austria

Assisted in delivering a Synergy method training, an intense personal development experience.

Facilitator, course designer - "Step Out Of Your Story"

08/2021, Erasmus+ Youth Exchange in Hungary

Challenging international project on storytelling, partially participant-driven and focused on inclusion. <u>Video.</u>

Trainer, co-designer - "Effective Planning"

07/2021, Erasmus+ Youth Exchange in Hungary

Project that blended time management skills and coding. Workshops on programming and computer science basics, as well as a very successful P5.js programming/animation course. Video.

Consultant - Symetics

01/2021

Created a course on JS graphical programming geared towards beginners for Symetics, meant to introduce them later on to web development.

Trainer, Designer - "Make Social Inclusion Happen"

09/2019, Erasmus+ Youth Exchange in Romania

Non-technical solo project, about minorities, social inclusion and identities. Ran educational workshops, games and bonding activities.

Trainer, Designer - "Gamification Exchanges"

06/2019, Erasmus+ Youth Exchange in Romania

A challenging re-implementation of "Design Your Game" (see

below). More focus on individual creativity and group dynamics than D.Y.G. Project video here.

Trainer, Designer - "Design Your Game"

04/2019, Erasmus+ Youth Exchange in Lithuania

My first E+ project, with self-employment as a twin topic. A bold initiative: to teach game development to international participants in under two weeks. Extremely well-received project that paved the way to the rest. Video here.

Data Analyst - Numeract

10/2017 - 03/2018

My first professional encounter with data science. I learned R and Python, and applied it in maintaining a data analysis project.

Trainer - MicroGear Arduino courses

03/2017, EU-funded project

Taught the basics of microcontroller programming in Arduino to groups of mixed age ranges, separated by skill level, overwhelming positive feedback on my ability to foster creativity and trust within the community.

Junior Front-end Dev - Levi9

12/2016 - 04/2017

Worked with various JS modules as part of a small team. Towards the end I succeeded in handling not only UI tasks, but also server construction and DB integration.

Education and certifications

UAIC Iasi - Computer Science Bachelor's 2015 - 2018

Final project: a neural network that uses superpixels to speed up the training process.

Trainer certificate - House of Arbitrage Iasi 09/2019

A training on educating adults, to make me a more well-rounded trainer, as I've mostly worked with kids and teens.

C2 CAE English Certificate (fluent/native)

Personal Projects / Other

Programming

- Data exploration with datasets from Kaggle (&etc.) and real-life observations
- JS and Lua mods for games I love, notably game automation and

- analytics
- Python and R, mostly in the context of data science and data analysis. Visualisations and art as well
- Al: genetic algorithms, neural networks, generative art
- Web: A browser-based game engine named Starspawn Engine
- Exploratory programming: generative art, fractals, genetic algorithm art
- (design phase) Dreamviz, a collage "engine"
- Languages and interpreters: Created several programming languages, notably the stack-based, syntax-less Vesper lang

Non-formal education

- Training and coaching courses
- Graphical facilitation training, "Sketching ideas"
- Volunteering in Erasmus and LGBTQ communities
- Various online courses on programming and art

Public Speaking

- Various animation workshops
- Social inclusion, minority identities and empathy activities
- Psychology and personality workshops
- Scientifical presentation at FameLab (won 3rd place)

Game Design: Itch Page

- Godot Engine games several prototypes and games, notably TTM, an inductive puzzle game
- QB Engine, Echo narrativist role-playing games, jam award winners
- Several board games, under playtesting Garish, Process(), After The Calamity
- Starspawn an experimental browser game (in pause)

Art

- Archonate a biopunk novel in progress
- Poetry, semi-traditional modern
- Spoken-word poetry
- First Days of Haven a series of short stories, in progress
- Mixed-media: ink, collage, acrylics, plant preservation
- Metalwork: tin-casting, wire-work